JASON BARRETT PRADO

jason.prado@gmail.com 650.575.9102 linkedin.com/in/jprado resume.jason.soy

Summary

I'm looking for challenging work that aligns with my values. I have a broad set of skills developed over a decade working at top technology firms. I'm a fast learner and I'm at my best when combining my talents in mentorship, communication, and engineering.

Work Experience

DATA ENGINEERING CONSULTANT, BERNIE SANDERS 2020, 2020

I advised the full-time campaign staff on engineering practices and built voter data pipelines using Amazon RedShift and dbt.

ENGINEER / ENGINEERING MANAGER, FACEBOOK, 2012-2020

2018-20	Lead Client Engineer on Novi Wallet for Libra. As one of the first engineers on Libra and the first staff on the user-facing product, I helped hire the initial Novi team and owned devising the overall product architecture.
2015-18	Engineering Manager for a team of 10 on an operating systems research project. I led an effort to build out novel methods for compiling production mobile applications.
2014-15	Started the Origami Studio design tool project.
2012-14	Client engineer on Facebook Paper for iOS.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, GOOGLE, 2010-2012

Tech Lead/Manager on Google Hangouts

FOUNDER, PLANNR, 2009-2010

Plannr was a social calendar app for iOS and Android. Plannr was acquired by Google in 2010.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, MICROSOFT, 2008-2009

Platform Graphics and Security on Silverlight

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, COOLIRIS, 2007-2008

Systems engineering on a 3D browser plugin

Education

Stanford University, B.S. Computer Science, 2008

Skills

iOS development (10 years) • Python (8 years) • Build Systems (5 years) C (5 years) • Java (2 years) • TypeScript (1 year) • SQL (intermediate) Web Frontend (hobby) • Kubernetes (hobby) • DevOps (hobby)